<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geosciences Programming</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Geosciences Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Epsilon Nd curve vs Age</title>
      <link>/post/epsilon-nd-curve-vs-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/epsilon-nd-curve-vs-age/</guid>
      <description>The epsilon Nd curve   The epsilon Nd (\(\epsilon_{Nd}\)) is a widely used parameter to understand the processes of rock forming, i.e. petrogenetic processes from both geochemical and geochronological approach. By definition, \(\epsilon_{Nd}\) is the difference of \(^{143}Nd/^{144}Nd\) of rock sample and ‘chondritic uniform reservoir’ at the time in the past T. For a rock of age T, \(\epsilon_{Nd}(T)\) is the ‘initial’ value of \(\epsilon_{Nd}\); the value at the time of crystallization of the rock, and \(\epsilon_{Nd}(0)\) is the measured value (dePaolo, 1981).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geochemical modelling of Ig. processes - Chapter 5: Radiogenic Isotopes</title>
      <link>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-5-radiogenic-isotopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-5-radiogenic-isotopes/</guid>
      <description>Calculation of Initial Ratios or Ages Exercise 5.1: Initial ratios and ages  Epsilon, Delta and Gamma Values Exercise 5.2: Epsilon Nd values  Model Ages Single-stage Nd model ages Exercise 5.3: Single-stage Nd model ages Two-stage Nd model ages Exercise 5.4: Two-stage Nd model ages  Isochron Ages Exercise 5.5: Isochrons    This post is a compilation of the exercises from Chapter 5: Radiogenic Isotopes from the book Geochemical Modelling of Igneous Processes - Principles and Recipes in R language by Vojtěch Janoušek, Jean Hervé Martin, Vojtěch Erban and Colin Farrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geochemical modelling of Ig. processes - Chapter 4: Specialized Plots</title>
      <link>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Log-log binary plots Specialized spider plots Contour plots   This post is a compilation of the exercises from Chapter 4: Specialized Plots from the book Geochemical Modelling of Igneous Processes - Principles and Recipes in R language by Vojtěch Janoušek, Jean Hervé Martin, Vojtěch Erban and Colin Farrow.
sink(&amp;quot;/dev/null&amp;quot;); suppressPackageStartupMessages(library(GCDkit)); sink(); Log-log binary plots data(sazava) par(mfrow=c(1,2)) # Split screen for 2 graphs par(mar=c(4,4,1,1)) # Outer margins for each of the graphs # Plot 1 plot(sazava[,&amp;quot;Sr&amp;quot;],sazava[,&amp;quot;Rb&amp;quot;],xlim=c(1,1000),ylim=c(1,1000),xlab=&amp;quot;Sr&amp;quot;,ylab=&amp;quot;Rb&amp;quot;,pch=16,col=&amp;quot;blue&amp;quot;,cex=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create hillshade in Python using earthpy</title>
      <link>/post/create-hillshade-in-python-using-earthpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/create-hillshade-in-python-using-earthpy/</guid>
      <description>This post create a hillshade topography map in Python using earthpy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geochemical Modelling of Ig. Processes - Chapter 3</title>
      <link>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geochemical-modelling-of-ig-processes-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Binary Plots Harker Plots and Other Basic Multiple Plots Ternary Plots Spider plot   This post is a compilation of the exercises from Chapter 3: Classical Plots from the book Geochemical Modelling of Igneous Processes - Principles and Recipes in R language by Vojtěch Janoušek, Jean Hervé Martin, Vojtěch Erban and Colin Farrow.
sink(&amp;quot;/dev/null&amp;quot;); suppressPackageStartupMessages(library(GCDkit)); sink(); In this chapter, I followed the examples from the book and modified the code where necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Syntax in a Nutshell III</title>
      <link>/post/r-syntax-in-a-nutshell-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-syntax-in-a-nutshell-iii/</guid>
      <description>Programming in R Conditional Execution Loops   Programming in R Input and Output Typical print message:
x &amp;lt;- 5.8 cat(&amp;quot;The result is&amp;quot;,x,&amp;quot;N/m.\n&amp;quot;) ## The result is 5.8 N/m. x &amp;lt;- readline(&amp;quot;Enter x: \n&amp;quot;) ## Enter x: x ## [1] &amp;quot;&amp;quot; x &amp;lt;- as.numeric(x) x ## [1] NA   Conditional Execution The traditional if… else… syntax in R
x &amp;lt;- 6 y &amp;lt;- 0.5 if (x&amp;gt;2 &amp;amp; y&amp;lt;1){ print(x) print(y) }else{ cat(&amp;quot;Warning, x&amp;lt;=2 or y&amp;gt;-1\n&amp;quot;) } ## [1] 6 ## [1] 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Syntax in a Nutshell Part II</title>
      <link>/post/r-syntax-in-a-nutshell-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-syntax-in-a-nutshell-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Graphics Obtaining and Annotating Binary Plots Additional High-level Plotting Functions Creating Custom Layouts and Axes Exporting Graphs from R and Graphical Devices  More info   Graphics R can produce and expert quite good publication-quality diagrams and they are divided into two types: high-level functions that open a new graphical window and set up a coordinate system (table A1.4) and low-level functions that annotate pre-existing plots (table A1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Adakite using Python</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-adakite-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-adakite-using-python/</guid>
      <description>We download the precompiled data of adakite from GEOROC database. For a simple impression of adakite, the wikipedia page gives some clue: Adakites are volcanic rocks of intermediate to felsic composition that have geochemical characteristics of magma thought to have formed by partial melting of altered basalt that is subducted below volcanic arcs.
In this example, we demonstrate how to use python to simplify the data, discard the null data, classify and plot the geochemical properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 15:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a website about using programing in Geochemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geochem modeling of Ig. Processes - Chapter 2</title>
      <link>/post/geochem-modeling-of-ig-processes-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geochem-modeling-of-ig-processes-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 2.1. Loading and Manipulating Data Exercise 2.1: Subsetting a numeric vector, vector operations Excercise 2.2: Loading files, matrix/data frame manipulations  2.2. Linking Whole-Rock Chemistry with Mineral Stoichiometry Exercise 2.3: Calculating simple indexes  2.3. Statistics Exercise 2.4: Simple statistics  2.4. Classification and Grouping - Using Factors Exercise 2.5. Using factors to deal with complex datasets I Exercise 2.6. Using factors to deal with complex datasets II Excercise 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Syntax in a Nutshell Part I</title>
      <link>/post/r-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-basics/</guid>
      <description>Seeking help Object types Numeric Vectors Character Vectors Arrays, Matrices, Data Frames Indexing/subsetting of Vectors, Arrays and Data Frames Lists Factors   Seeking help First step in doing any programming is to know where to seek help. Here demonstrate how to seek help in R programming. These keywords include: help(), ?, apropos and example.
help(plot) ?plot apropos(&amp;quot;plot&amp;quot;) #Commands related to &amp;quot;plot&amp;quot; ## [1] &amp;quot;assocplot&amp;quot; &amp;quot;barplot&amp;quot; &amp;quot;barplot.default&amp;quot; ## [4] &amp;quot;biplot&amp;quot; &amp;quot;boxplot&amp;quot; &amp;quot;boxplot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>